it made me recognize one thing that's
very important about your career is how
you interview is the most it's the
highest leverage most important part of
your career like more important than the
impact you even have on the role it's
crazy what you just said is probably one
of the most important lessons that I
learned at Facebook if you were to start
all over again as ic3 knowing what you
know today M what's one thing that You'
change today I'd like to share a
conversation that I had with Zach Wilson
he's an engineer That Grew From Junior
meta to staff engineer at Airbnb by the
age of 26 two of his promotions came
from job hopping which got me curious so
we go into those details we go over his
ratings his compensation and a bunch
more along the way I think you'll like
it since Zach is really transparent with
everything so if this sounds interesting
to you here's the Pod first thing is you
breaking into big Tech can you run me
through that story where were you in
your life how did you get into big Tech
yeah for sure so I started my career at
a bunch of different startups started
off as like a data analyst because I had
dreams of being a math professor for a
while and then I realized like that's
probably not what I want to do because
it's a lot of school to make not very
much money and then I was like okay
probably need to switch and then I was
in started as an analyst I got in at
this company called think big analytics
where they taught me Hadoop but they
taught me Hadoop really a long time ago
it was like 10 years ago now so it was
like right when Hadoop was really early
and uh I owe that experience I feel like
to like the main reason why I got in at
Facebook because that's what they were
looking for was like those kind of Big
Data Technologies and so I jumped around
a lot though because I tried out four
different jobs in two years to like and
then I got the job at Facebook and yeah
it was pretty chaotic because I didn't
know what I wanted to do actually cuz
when I graduated I actually was like I
want to be a mobile engineer but I also
want to be math professor but I also
want to be a data scientist and I was
like I and I just was like okay I need
to do all of these roles at least for a
little bit to understand which one I
want and that's when I landed on data
engineering and I was like all right
this one seems like it fits so were you
a CS major I did the dual major Cs and
applied math dual major yeah I actually
math was first I I finished my math
major first and then got the Cs major
later how was the job market when you
applied for interviews were you able to
get interview yeah I think right now is
a challenging time but I definitely
found that like when I first graduated I
interviewed bunch of places government
jobs cuz like where I grew up there's
tons of like government jobs on a
military base like interviewed there
interviewed in Salt Lake and all across
the valley I probably got four five
different interviews though like with no
experience and just like the only
experience I had was I was a math tutor
that was all I had so yeah I feel very
lucky that was like my getting into the
industry experience for sure these were
CS jobs yeah uh CS an analyst like it
was like those two I was trying to
decide between the two because yeah the
government job was going to be a CS role
I actually ended up not taking that role
though yeah okay so how did you find
your way into Facebook then yeah so it
was wild because so I did one year in
Utah and then I got like very frustrated
with Utah then I moved to DC because I
was like I'm just want to leave my home
state want to try something new I was in
DC for six seven months and then that's
when a Facebook recruiter reached out to
me and they were like hey you should
interview and I'm like this is wild cuz
back in Utah I did interview at Google
twice actually for Mobile and got
rejected both times and so I was like it
but I applied to Google and I it felt
very magical when it was like the
Facebook recruiter reached out to me I
was like I felt like Facebook was
applying to me almost I was like okay
yeah sure I'll give an interview was
that through Linkedin or yeah LinkedIn
for sure linkedin's been so critical for
my whole career since that job at think
big like in 2015 at the time you didn't
post on LinkedIn no definitely not
definitely not like I do now okay so
they inbounded and then you interviewed
with them MH and you got the role and
was the interview explicitly for data
engineer yes I see I see okay so then
you got the role do were you applying to
other places at the same time no
actually I was pretty happy with my role
in DC there was a lot of trajectory
there it was interesting cuz when I got
the offer from Facebook my role in DC
countered with more money actually and I
was like whoa I was not expecting them
to they were like here's 100% raise and
I but the thing was I didn't take it
because two months before I asked them
for a 20% raise and they said they
didn't have the budget and I was like
okay if y'all only have the budget when
I have my foot out the door I know that
career growth here is going to be
painful it's going to be super painful
even though it's more money even though
it's a cheaper place to live I'm going
to California for less money and a more
expensive place to live because I
believe in the future oh so actually
Facebook paid you less it was a raise
based off of what I was making but the
counter offer that I got from my company
in DC was more money I see I see it was
like 180 was what Facebook offered me
and then they countered with 200 one
think okay okay sounds good so then you
got into Facebook as a data engineer how
was the moving to Silicon Valley and I
loved it like I there was a couple other
motivating factors for me to come back
to California because I grew up in Utah
and like being a DC being far away from
family all that stuff was like also
isolating and being in California is
really nice cuz I'm still pretty close
to Utah I can drive home any day I want
in one day if I want to do that but
getting into Silicon Valley was really
great it was really wonderful I really
felt especially those like first couple
days like those boot camp tasks that
they give you and they're like go and do
this scavenger hunt right I don't know
it always like my that first like month
at Facebook didn't even feel like I was
like working a job it felt like I was in
like Disneyland it felt like I was this
is a job like I'm going to work here it
didn't really it it it was very good at
getting me to adopt move fast and break
things this is your company be bold all
those like kind of tenants of Facebook
that like it because it was such a great
onboarding experience I was like wow
this company is something else I love
boot camp it felt like an extension of
college or something because you're
going to all these classes you're just
learning you're not being held
accountable for any deadlines or
anything yet so that was really great
okay so you come into boot camp how did
you pick the team that you were in great
question so I had three choices I was
either going to join ads I was going to
join growth or I was going to join
Community Support those are the three
that they had me interview with and
essentially for me it was like which one
was different with ads they were like if
you come in here you're going to provide
data that's going to make Facebook
millions and I'm like wow interesting
impact and then for Community Support
they were like if you come in here you
can help prevent a lot of bad stuff on
Facebook and then growth they're like if
you join us you'll have a lot of fun and
I was like sold and I ended up joining
growth I think it was a combination of
that and then the manager was more of
this entrepreneurial stupy guy his name
is jender he's going to make a couple
other cameo appearances in the rest of
this podcast but he was great guy really
great guy he's still one of my best
friends to this day and that's why I
ended up picking core growth and
notifications specifically when you
joined did you know much about the
career ladder or were you thinking about
it no there was so many things I didn't
know for example like I actually didn't
even understand like L3 L4 L5 I I didn't
understand I didn't understand that I
was getting hired in at L3 because one
of the things that like really was
disconcerting to me when I got in at
Facebook was like I had two years of
experience I'd been working in startups
and doing big data pipelines for two
years and then there's these kids from
Stanford who get hired and they get paid
the same as me with zero years of
experience and I was like this is unfair
and I re that was one of the things I
recognized pretty early on in my time at
Facebook which also I think spoiled my
time at Facebook is because I recognized
hey like I got hired at the wrong level
so I need to bust my ass to get to the
next level which I did it was like like
seven months from I was only L3 for a
very short amount of time but I think
that was something that definitely
bothered me as I I recognized it made me
recognize one thing that's very
important about your career is how you
interview is the most it's the highest
leverage most important part of your
career like more important than the
impact you even have on the role it's
crazy like yeah one of the things that
interests me most in your story is you
were able to successfully interview into
promotions multiple times and I think a
lot of people wonder how you do that I'm
myself I'm also curious what were those
conversations like when you having the
interviews how did you get placed in the
staff how did you get placed in the
senior but yeah we'll go into that later
in the podcast so you got promoted in
one half so what how did that work was
that expected or I recognized pretty
early on that I was going to succeed at
Facebook just because of I like how
everything was tasked out and how there
was just I had a lot of energy and I
could tell that I was shipping a lot of
code and I was moving a lot of things
and I picked up notifications very
quickly so like they had this like
waterfall framework for notifications
which is like essentially tracking like
conversion rates or clicked rates or
delivery rates all those different like
funnel metrics that you can do they had
this whole framework for that but the
framework sucked and one of the reasons
why I got that promotion was I was also
like let's fix the framework but one of
the things about that was like that was
actually like xhp work that was not like
SQL python work at all and like when my
manager saw that I I was like I'm just
going to fix it just going to go and
learn xhp and react and fix it and he
was like wow this guy knows how to solve
a problem like even when it's not in
data engineering it's it's a full stack
problem and that was something I
demonstrated really early on to my
manager was that like I'm not going to
let a skill set or think that's not my
problem it's I'm going to learn and
figure out like what needs to be done
and solve the problem and yeah for sure
it was did anyone tell you to to do that
or no not really I think that's the
other part of why I grew really close
with this manager as well is because I
recognized like where the impact is
right not just being like okay I'm going
to finish my tasks and be done with it
that's how you get meets all finish your
tasks do them as they were assigned
especially at L3 if you do exactly what
your task says you'll get meets all and
it's going to be great but if you want
to do more which I was very hungry to do
more especially when I realized that I
was hired in at the wrong level I was
like okay I have to just get out of this
situation as quickly as possible so
that's why I also did those things
because I wanted to demonstrate to them
like I have experience I'm a skilled
person and yeah for sure did the promo
just happen or were you aware of it and
expecting that to come at any point not
the promo did just happen like that
first promo that had no idea your
manager was yeah because a couple things
about it was like I actually got it
wasn't even a full half because I got
hired in at the end of July so I missed
a month of that half as well so it was
five months so but like definitely the
that that promo just was like I think
they recognized that I was hired at the
wrong level and that's why they gave it
to me it they weren't going to make me
like do all the steps of getting there
or whatever yeah yeah usually when
motions happen in just a half yeah that
means that was mis leveling and that's
an opportunity if you just joined
Facebook and you all of a sudden were
performing as ic5 they'll just promote
you quickly because they take that as it
was a Miss on the hiring and I think
that's one of the things that is really
cool about working there and about these
tech companies is that they will do that
because it's not I don't know at least
like growing up in Utah and everything
it's not based on impact it's based on
tenure right it's based on okay been
here three years okay you're a senior
engineer now and it's based on just like
amount of time in the role and that was
probably one of the most beautiful
things that shifted my mentality when I
moved to the Bay Area because when I was
in Utah I thought that the very most
money that I was going to make in my
career as a software engineer was 200k
200k was going to be and that was like
15 years deep that's why that was me
imagining myself at 35 and then when I
get in at Facebook and I'm like no
they're like okay no we're going to give
you 200k now and there's a freaking
trajectory to go to a million if you
want and it really showed me that
there's so much more to this life and so
much more to like engineering than just
I'm working at a company I'm closing
Jura tickets but it's if you actually
start to care about the impact of the
business like it they reward you right
they give back it's awesome because you
can create so much value too you
actually make more than you cost it's
easy for them to Warrant paying you that
much oh yeah for sure it's okay it's
like you save us 10 mil we'll give you a
little bit more money sure yeah
sometimes when people save 10 mil I'm
like just give me a little 1% I'll take
a little bit yeah yeah yeah okay so you
got promoted from 3: to 4 yeah because
you had insane initiative sounds like
you were working a lot of hours how many
hours a week would you say uh so after
boot camp I ramped up I would say
probably 50 to 60 very common I think
for me where it would be like I would
get in at 9 9:30 and then I would stay
till 8 8 at night cuz i' do breakfast
lunch and dinner TR all meals cuz you
know I'm still this way I feel like this
is one of the things where Facebook
ruined me a little bit is that they're
like we're just going to feed you all
your meals and then I'm like now I'm 30
and I'm like I still don't know how to
cook and I'm like this is a problem I'm
like it's a basic life skill that I was
able to avoid learning and I'm like this
is a rough situation but definitely I
would say yeah around that got it you
know so then after you got pred to four
then well were you hungry for five oh
yeah when I got four I was like I want
five in a year and I was like I'm going
to work for it I'm going to crush it and
yeah and it didn't happen so what was
your plan did you talk to your manager
yeah I did I talked with my manager so a
couple things happened that I and jender
like that when he was my manager I
actually was pretty confident that it
was going to happen problem was that
next summer jender left and then there
was a period of time where we all just
reported to the director right and I
didn't really have a great relationship
with him and then eventually we got a
new guy in right and it's funny cuz that
guy came from Netflix which is so
bizarre ultimately because then I left
to Netflix I'm like Netflix and Facebook
are all it's all the same people dude
but I had a plan and I actually felt
like I actually did deliver on the value
that was necessary to get to senior but
and my view on it was the fact that I
had three managers that year I had
jender I had Nick and I had sat and no
one really had the context right because
I'm like how many times do I have to
tell my manager what I did why do I have
to do this again and again and and I
think that was ultimately the thing that
kind of disrup rupted the plan but it
also goes to show that having a good
manager who trusts you takes time and
you have to build that up with them you
have to prove that to them right and
they're not like the good managers will
trust like implicitly and then they will
only remove trust when you give them a
reason to not trust you but some
managers are like no you got to prove it
right that's where it's like different
it depends on who your manager is so you
had jender for a half or how he was my
manager for a little bit over a year but
so after you got promoted yeah that
first half did he do your PSC that half
yeah for the promotion yeah for the for
just yeah he did the first promotion but
after that no no not the because he left
after that okay yeah half as an E4 yeah
and then you got a new manager yeah and
that half though how's your PSC was it I
got greatly exceeds okay you got greatly
exceeds as an E4 in your first half okay
yeah that's signal that you're doing
really well yeah what prevented the
promotion the next time great question I
think what happened the next half was it
was greatly again right like got and
what they were saying was that like I
was not operating as a senior engineer
because I was still focusing too much on
problems that I like that they were like
you're taking on too much work and that
they're like you are delivering as an E5
but you like they they their belief was
that I would not sustainably deliver
like that that was and I'm like which
was something that like pissed me off a
lot definitely a thing that comes up
it's a bummer because you would think
that the harder you work the more you
would get rewarded with promotions but
one of the things they're looking for is
that your promotion's sustainable and
it's funny because if you're working a
lot to get those results people might
wonder oh can he keep this up yeah what
if he starts working normal hours MH is
he not going to meet expectations 100%
that's that was right there what you
just said is probably what of the most
important lessons that I learned at
Facebook which is that hours work does
not necessarily influence like your
promotion ability there is a point where
it's like hours work helps with
addressing like skill gaps if you have a
gap then you can cover the Gap by
working more but that does not
necessarily instill confidence and
Leadership that you are promotion worthy
right for sure definitely because
they're looking for behaviors they're
looking for someone that can take on
more leadership not necessarily just
work additional hours to have the impact
so get it but also at the same time it
can be you know pretty something that
can make a hard worker very salty yeah
yeah and I think for me what ended up
happening was that next like going into
the next year because those promos
usually happen in like March or whatever
and I after learning I'm like I'm not
getting promoted I was like time to go
and take the story because this is one
of the things I think is super important
when you think about interviewing is I
knew that I had a story that would get
me a senior role because guess what
Facebook told me that they said I was
greatly exceeding expectations and guess
what know the best part about
interviewing is they don't know how many
hours I worked they just know what I did
right they don't know how many hours I
work they like in the interview they get
a different vantage point of what your
impact was and what you did and they
don't get as much of the negative data
right they don't get as much of that and
so for me recognized that I was like I
know I can go to any other big tech
company and be a senior engineer I
already knew that especially like after
all the optimizations I made the
notification machine learning algorithm
all that stuff there was like some very
technical nitty-gritty things that I did
that were really impactful that I was
like I know if I just talk about that in
the detail that I know people are going
to give me what I want so to be clear
you got two great League seeds in a row
as ic4 yeah which is midlevel and then
you didn't get promoted so instantly you
realized okay because I'm greatly
exceeding I can get ic5 somewhere else
yeah 100% And also the thing that
blocked your promotion it's not going to
be a blocker somewhere else yep yeah for
sure okay so then how did you sell that
as a ic5 to the next place cuz when I
think of what qualifies for an ic5 if
you're interviewing they'll say yeah
certain number of years of experience
and various other things they might also
want to know what level you are at meta
so how did you get Netflix level as an
ic5 when you're midlevel not that many
years of experience I feel like the
Netflix one was there was also one more
element of luck here and that element of
luck is that the hiring manager was
jender so I'm like all right jender
you've already seen my work you trust me
what's up and so that helped a lot like
having the right connections that's why
building a network is important that's
why I'm all about brand personal brand
and I think a lot of people conflate
personal branding with making content on
LinkedIn or like putting your voice or a
blog post or making YouTube videos or
whatever but there's also like this idea
of internal brand which is like how are
you known in the company how are you
known by the people you work with and
it's if you are if you're able to build
a strong internal brand that's what it
did it's because I worked really hard
with jender and he saw what I was
capable of and capable of doing because
for me there was one other problem that
I had with Facebook actually which was I
and there was one other conversation
that I had that like really frustrated
me was I also wanted to not be a data
engineer anymore right cuz I was like
I'm done because I've been shipping so
much like react and PHP and hack code
and all this stuff and I even was
talking to my managers like dude like
compared to all the other data Engineers
on this team I am writing I'm I because
I even gave him the number I'm like of
so I was on a team of 15 data engineers
and I'm like I'm writing 90% of the
JavaScript code from our team me just me
and so it's I am not doing the same work
that like other data Engineers are doing
so I feel like I should not be a data
engineer I should be a software engineer
and software engineers get more Equity
because because data Engineers are
technically not on the E Track like
their IC track they're like and so they
get like it's like 30 40% less equity
which is I was like that was the other
thing I was like unfair I'm a software
engineer I'm a real engineer and so
there was one more conversation I had
there that like really set me off that
made me like really not want to work at
Facebook anymore which was like so one
was like I really wanted to be like L5
and the other one was I wanted to switch
the song software engineer and when I
talked with my manager about switching
software engineer they were like hey we
can switch you to software engineer
we're gonna have to down level you
though and I'm like I'm not going to be
an L3 software engineer that is absurd
that is patently absurd for me to do
that that is an absurd statement that
you even said that came out of your
mouth right there why they were like
you're not going to have all the skills
necessary for it and again that was the
thing where I point what about the stuff
I'm shipping B's code over here see this
stuff I've already built and that stuff
didn't matter they they just looked at
title and comes back to having the right
manager matters so much it matters so
much because then they're actually able
to listen to your career goals and
actually take into account all of those
things right they're not just your data
engineer so and for a while that was
actually like standard practice at
Facebook if you wanted to go from data
engineer to software engineer they down
leled you but not the other way around
which I always thought was interesting
I'm like okay so there's like this
software engineer Supremacy at Facebook
or something like that where they're
like yeah software Engineers are here
data Engineers are here it's yeah for
sure that's where that was the other
thing I recognized was I wanted to work
on data stuff that wasn't just SQL
because now I learned more and like the
field has changed data engineering has
changed and technically the role I had
at Facebook was not data engineering it
would not be titled that today today it
would be titled analytics engineering
which a different title right and that's
like more sequal experimentation product
analytics focused whereas data
engineering is more about like big data
pipelines and like spark and so more
Technical and not not as much analytical
and and that I was drawn more to that
kind of stuff as well so do you think if
you had a better manager that you
wouldn't have been downlevel oh no I
definitely not if I would have had a
more supportive manager there that I
would have been able to tr because guess
what I have a friend who works at
Facebook his name is also Ryan and he
still works at Facebook and guess what
his manager was supportive and he
transitioned this week and he I've
always I always look at his life and I'm
like your life is the life I would have
had if I didn't have a bad manager and
he's still there he's been at meta like
nine years now he's been there for a
long time he's doing all all this crazy
stuff like scuba and stuff like that
good stuff but like for sure definitely
that is definitely uh something that I
believe especially because when I was
talking with jender at Netflix he was
like hey I don't know if I can hire you
in as a senior software engineer because
you don't have very much experience in
software engineering but he was like I
can hire you in as a senior data
engineer and then I can get you to
transition to software engineer in six
to six to 12 months and I was like
perfect perfect that sounds great and so
that's what ended up happening I got
hired in at Netflix was there for six
months and then the rest of my time at
Netflix I was senior software engineer
and I I worked didn't really do as much
data pipeline work got it okay so going
back to your transition from Facebook to
Netflix yeah it was a connection with
your old manager who gave gave you such
a strong recommendation that you were
put into a senior pipeline yep and
Netflix only hired seniors okay so there
wasn't any it was senior or you're not
in it's different now they added levels
like two years ago but yeah back in 2018
there was no staff either were you
working directly on his team or yeah he
was my direct manager yeah was his
recommendation especially powerful cuz
like I can recommend people The Meta but
it's not especially powerful or anything
the reason for that is because meta has
more standardized interview processes
that's not how it is at Netflix at
Netflix it's freedom and responsibility
and they give managers a lot of power at
Netflix right they also give managers a
lot of power to fire people and they put
a lot of pressure on managers to fire
people but also the hiring process is up
to them yeah so that's also who they
bring on is there it's more free I'm
sure these things have changed a little
bit because I think that actually that
aspect of Netflix's culture has minuses
as well it's not it's not all pluses I
think there is definitely some pluses
and I benefited from some of those
pluses for sure and initially like when
I was there I was like wow this is the
best company ever how many Engineers
were at the company at the time total at
Netflix I think like a thousand or maybe
1500 it's quite a bit bigger now I think
it's 3K now but yeah it was like yeah
but definitely like over a thousand got
it okay but not Facebook size right
Facebook is like 10 15,000 I was like a
lot right yeah yeah okay so you
essentially earned your senior position
as an ic3 cuz you proved yourself to to
jender as a junior engineer yeah as a
junior engineer he thinks okay this guy
to results yeah and then later when he
was building up his team it was just a
matter of oh I know that guy's good I
want him on regardless of all the level
stuff yeah I know he's going to deliver
and I want him on my team and so that
got you in to get that promotion from
mid-level to senior yeah okay wow okay
so internal brand really does matter
then it matters a lot it matters way
more than you think and and so that's
why it's important to like not really
burn Bridges with people but also find
those people who you really click with
and because you never know you might be
working with them again in the future
yeah definitely and that was a good jump
CU if you would have just stayed at
Facebook you are already greatly
exceeding so what more yeah you could
change your behaviors and go through the
promo process but that would have been
slower than just going directly into
Netflix definitely yeah and so was that
compensation bump from oh yeah it was
like almost double your compensation
doubled from I what was it it was like
two it was like two with L4 to
385 390 like and but all cash all cash
wow okay that's pretty good yeah and so
how was your time at Netflix were you
thinking I guess they didn't have a
notion of promotions there CU it's just
all senior yeah all senior yeah so your
what was your thinking you wanted to
transition to software engineer M you
did that where were you thinking to go
from there with your career so from
there I wanted to like I had a vision I
had a vision of myself it's crazy that I
walked away from a year ago but like I
was 24 when I got on Netflix I had a
vision that I was by the time I was 30 I
was going to be a principal engineer
like L7 L8 like and in big Tech doing
just really technical deep stuff and
that was my vision and I knew that I was
not going to get there in data
engineering and that was one of the
other reasons why I knew I needed to
make the switch yeah for sure and
Netflix was really crazy cuz it was like
very different instead of doing like
regular like data pipelines that were
like once a day processing it was like
everything had to be in real time to
detect security threats it was like very
different very like Cutting Edge very
like difficult work for sure so then if
you wanted to get to principle how are
you going to do that on Netflix great
question so at Netflix how it works is
essentially every year there is a
compensation discussion but again they
don't have performance reviews either
there's no performance reviews
technically there are performance
reviews at Netflix but they're every
quarter where your manager gives you a
color you either get green yellow or red
as a color where red means you're going
to be fired imminently yellow means you
need to pick it up and green means
you're good you get that feedback every
quarter which is a lot once a year they
do have an annual compensation
discussion but you don't talk about what
you did it's all about what you could
get in the market from other companies
and they they'll match you and but your
manager could also if they feel like
you're being underpaid or whatever they
can also come in and adjust your
competition like almost at any time it's
very different a lot fewer rules than at
meta where it's got to be like every six
months after a calibration and a packet
and a submission it's a whole thing
Netflix is very different but I think
Netflix has learned because Netflix
obviously there's levels now and I think
that was a problem I think for me the
thing that I recognized and why I didn't
really care that much about oh there's
no levels here was one I knew I was
going to make a ton of money two I knew
I was working with jender and that I
knew that I still had so much more to
learn from I still do because I talk
with him about entrepreneurship stuff
now but anyways I had so much to learn
from him and I was like wherever this
goes it's going to go and I know I can
have a good story it comes back to like
wherever you're at always think about
your story about the impact that you had
at the company and what you did and make
it sound like a movie man make it sound
cool make it sound like dude you did
some really cool [__] that's like a very
important part of the journey since I
have a tendency to leave jobs every two
years or so I always have to feel like
I'm satisfied with the story because
that that's something that happened at
Airbnb where I actually had an urge to
quit earlier but then I realized I was
like wait a minute I don't have a story
yet I don't have a really good story yet
so I stayed six more months but yeah
getting that impact story is super
important so when you say story you just
mean a good fully
delivered package of work that was
impactful yeah you can sell yep 100%
exactly where it's like hey if you hire
me I will do this much for you in two
years got it okay for instance at meta
what was your story what did you use to
sell to okay so at meta I did a a couple
things one was in notifications I
developed the reachability metric which
was a good counterweight to prevent
spamming on notifications because I
don't if growth goes up the more
notifications you send there's a
correlation there but obviously there's
a spam on the other side and so
reachability was like determining who is
turning off their settings uh which just
a way more complicated metric than you
would think so that's one big thing I
did another big thing was built the
first crossa growth dashboard for
WhatsApp Instagram messenger and
Facebook so you could look at all of the
growth metrics in one chart and that had
never been done before was the the
engineer that integrated all that stuff
the big thing was Facebook has this
algorithm called nudges The Machine
learning Al algorithm that determines
which notifications to send to you I
made that pipeline 90 it cost 90% less
so it was 10 times more efficient after
I optimized it with this thing called
sorted merge bucket joins but those are
the main things that I did in at my time
at Facebook that I sold to Netflix that
you're saying for successful job hopping
you want to wrap those pieces up and be
thinking about when I jump this is the
story I'm going to tell about the thing
that I did yeah because obviously if you
have short tenure at places the very
first thing they're going to think is
this guy doesn't play well with others
this guy is he's not a good fit there
why is he going to be a good fit with us
but you have to squash that very early
in the interview process you have to
squash the idea of this guy is a
disloyal job Hopper because that's
obviously something they're going to
think when they look at the resume but
if you can squash that and instead be
like no this guy is actually extremely
ambitious he wants to solve hard
problems and he has solved hard problems
and he's on a trajectory to help us
solve hard problems that is a much
better more I've even seen it in
interviews where people were initially
skeptical of me but after talking with
me they're like okay this guy seems
pretty good so let's talk about rvnv so
I guess for the promotion to senior it
was through the job hop Contender was a
big part of it and your ability to sell
yourself was a big part of it so then
sounds like Netflix was good what made
you want to jump to to Airbnb great
question a couple things happened so
like one of the things that happened
with jender was he also believed in me
too much cuz what ended up happening on
my team at Netflix was I was on this
team working on security threat
detection but then there was a whole
other team doing this thing called asset
inventory just us managing all of the
cloud assets and where they're at and
who owns all that stuff and the engineer
there who had been at Netflix for 10
years left the team there was this
opening for that spot which was why
Netflix is complicated back then
especially complicated that spot was
definitely a staff spot not a senior
spot I'm like I'll take it let's go I'm
hungry for opportunity and I'll take it
and so I take that role I went from
interfacing with just the detection team
to interfacing with 11 other teams the
amount of conversations that I needed to
have dramatically skyrocketed I honestly
wasn't ready for that and I leaned back
into my behavior okay these people want
this these people want that and I'm like
okay I'm just going to answer all these
people's questions even though I was
just one guy and it was way too much
work I got to solve all these problems
because I was like holy crap this is
crazy and I got a big raise though I got
a huge raise from that because of that
that jump into this new role Netflix
recognized that so when they when I got
in I was in like the upper 300s and then
my next year at Netflix like they had me
at 550 and because of this like change
into this kind of more of a staff
engineer archetype which was not ready
for and then ultimately what ended up
happening at Netflix was in
2019 they decided that data engineering
and data science so I was still I was a
software engineer on a data engineering
team it's complicated okay but like I
was still in the data engineering orc
and so the data engineering they
determined that data engineering was no
longer like a necessary org and they
wanted to collapse it into data science
okay and so they like what they did was
they straight up they like okay VP fired
director fir fired and then jender fired
they just cut the whole chain and then
they're like okay now all you guys
report to the data science people now
and like when they did that when they
did that like that stressed me out a lot
it stressed me out way too much I it was
stressed me out so much that I went on a
mental health break I went on Mental
Health break because I was like this is
too much this is too much and then I
went on Mental Health break for a month
then I came back and then I realized I
was like I wanted to work with your
tender man like I don't know so he
wasn't part of the data science or he
was a data engineering leader oh was he
fired he was fired yeah no they fired
all the data engineering leaders oh they
all got God and then we all started
reporting to data science leaders
instead and that was a big thing that I
was like there was one last I had one
last attempt that I wanted to do at
Netflix because technically I also
wasn't really in the data engineering
org to begin with I was more in like the
Cyber Security Org because I was working
on asset inventory and tracking all like
the security assets that was like
literally what my job was and so the
very last thing I tried was I was like
tedo's gone I don't want to work in a
data science org I did that at Facebook
I did not like it I want to be in an
engineering org right not an analytics
org that's why I'm here that's why I
that was my original reason of coming
here and so the last thing I did was I
applied to transition to the cyber
security team and I was like Hey makes a
lot of sense I'm like the only software
engineer on this data engineering team
so it doesn't even make sense that I'm
on this team so I think it makes more
sense that I'm on your guys' team and
then they were like they didn't that
transfer they didn't like the idea of
that transfer and they were like no like
you should stay in your current role and
I was like all right Deuces see you
later and that pissed me off a lot that
pissed me off a lot because then I'm
like okay there's what am I supposed to
do here I'm just supposed to just shut
up and write pipelines is that what I'm
supposed to do in this situation when
literally they just completely changed
the org in a way that it no longer
aligns with my career goals so
ultimately I just quit I was like I'm
done with nothing lined up I actually
had a dream of traveling the world
that's what I wanted to do I wanted to
spend 2020 travel the world so I quit in
early March 6th 2020 was my last day of
Netflix I was like I'm going to travel
the world the timing was absolutely
atrocious then the world was like no
you're not going to travel because Co
happen and I was like wow okay but yeah
I just was like I'm done I'm going to
just not work at this company anymore
just felt like I wanted to give so much
to that company they were like we're
going to give you nothing of what you
want we'll pay you a lot but we're going
to give you absolutely nothing else I'm
like okay then there's the whole adage
of like in your career you should be
learning or earning or both I am still
even today I'm All About Learning is
still better than earning even now even
where I'm at that's why I'm like
entrepreneur now because I want to learn
new things I want to attack new problems
and solve new problems and it's that's
why I got bored at Airbnb because I'm
like I'm not learning sure I'm making
great money but I'm not really learning
so I want to do something else and and I
think that's not why people work at
Netflix though they're more motivated
there to make a lot of money and retire
early that's the main motivation for
people there I actually think that
people at meta are more learning
motivated yeah for sure okay so yeah
there was one thing that you said in
your last story of what you were doing
in Netflix at the end there y you said
you got put into a staff role and you
weren't ready for it yeah I think that
is the thing that these big tech
companies try to prevent when they don't
promote someone because they don't have
the behaviors but they have the impact
mhm because you had the skills and
everything but then you were put in
there and it was just too much stuff you
needed the staff behaviors to scale
yourself and work through other people
so I thought that was a pretty good
example of I think when I heard the
lagging promotion stuff I go why are you
holding people back yeah but this is the
exact meant to me prevent this situation
right where if these people are like
they have the impact for it but they
don't have the behaviors like looking
back on it at Netflix like the big thing
for me was a couple things I think one
was establishing better work boundaries
super important one another one was like
just like planning things out a little
bit more and not it's one of those
things that like I recognize now that's
actually the part that is again it's the
lesson I'm learning again as an
entrepreneur it's the lesson I learned
then and I'm learning again as you do
still need to plan things out and be
like okay this is going to happen later
it doesn't have to happen today but it
will happen at some point in the future
right those things and I think another
big one was just like selling a vision
right selling like a technical vision of
something that was in my head and and
this is something content has helped me
a lot with is like being able to take
ideas that I have in my head that I'm
very excited about but then actually
being able to present them and and show
them and sell other people on them I
think that's one of the big behaviors
that changes is that you do need to be
able to sell you have to be able to sell
like a vision or a future we need to be
working on this not that and those are
things that like in all the previous
levels of engineering you don't have to
worry about you just deliver on the work
that you're supposed to deliver on and
solve the hard problem but deciding on
which problem to solve that was the
other Behavior at Netflix that I was
like I'm like whoa dude I'm like I don't
know yeah yeah for sure okay going back
to the story timeline yeah so now you
left Netflix cuz there was reorgs chaos
you don't have anything else lined up
yep how do you start thinking about
Airbnb oh yeah it really just came back
to in December of 2020 when after I was
like had played a lot of video games and
I I don't know I just wasn't feeling
very fulfilled I was really depressed
and then my my girlfriend at the time
was like what are you doing with your
life what's going on and she was like
very not happy with what I was doing and
I was like fair and we ended up breaking
up and I was like whoa this is okay now
I'm like I got no job I got no
girlfriend I'm like and I barely got the
dog getting the breakup but okay we got
the dog and that's just me and a dog
right now I'm like I got to freaking
support my dog at least with an income
and then I was like I should interview I
should like I should take another swing
at the fences here and see what happens
I also so that was also when I started
making content was December 2020 was
like that was because that was also
something I said to all my co-workers at
Netflix when I quit I was like you're
gonna see me again you're gonna see me
again I'm GNA be famous I promise I I I
told them all that in like March of 2020
when I left because I was like I'm going
to make content I'm going to be I even
knew back then I was going to make
content but I should have done it during
the pandemic when everyone was on their
phone because you could just blow up and
then you could be like Ali Miller and
have 1.5 million followers if you
started in 2020 you got such an unfair
advantage and Ali Miller she's like the
number one AI influencer on LinkedIn but
yeah I was just happy that I started in
2020 still and then that was the big
things I did I started making content on
LinkedIn and then I started applying I
actually interviewed at more than just
Airbnb I interviewed at meta I
interviewed at Google and I interviewed
at Airbnb when you interviewed was it uh
data engineer data engineering roles it
was a mix actually cuz I didn't know
what I wanted cuz Airbnb was able to end
up selling on a data engineering role
but at Google I interviewed for software
engineer and at Facebook I interviewed
for software engineer and I actually got
offers from all three companies but the
problem was that the Google and Facebook
roles were both senior and I was like
and then every VI was like and I'm like
okay and then it was just like I was
like I can't just say no to an extra
$100,000 because it was just like the
Airbnb offer was just so much more money
that it was like okay this is not even
close do you remember what the numbers
were yeah so for Facebook it was like
415 or something like that like it was
pretty high like 400 and then Google's
was a little bit like three when I got
the offer from Google I was like why did
I even interview with you guys you're
going to pay me what Netflix paid me
four years ago I don't know about that
and then the one from airb came in out
was like and I was like okay it's much
more over $100,000 more and I was like
okay freaking easy decision easy
decision yeah no brainer yeah it made me
a little bit sad cuz I was like it's not
even really competing offers because
those ones aren't even really comp
competing with the other one and I was
like it was an interesting of place to
be but the reason why I was okay with it
because Airbnb actually does data
engineering very differently than uh a
lot of other companies big things like
for example at Airbnb I only coded in
Scala right no Sequel and I guess not
only Scala but like 95% Scala and 5%
python but because it's all about they
want really high quality pipelines that
are integrated with their online systems
like with for me it was pricing and
availability their pric availability
systems they wanted pipelines that
emulated all of the behavior that those
systems would create and that's what I
worked on and I'm like this is not
really even this is a good it actually
felt very amazing at first because I was
like this is exactly what I wanted at
Netflix cuz I'm like it's the perfect
blend of creating pipelines but also
still having technical Integrations and
optimization concerns that you have to
also think about and dealing with online
systems it was like this crazy like role
that was in the middle that I really
liked but yeah it was an interesting one
for sure so Airbnb gives you staff
that's a no-brainer and it makes it so
that you're willing to go back in the
data engineering software engineering
okay sounds good the big question for me
is how are you able to sell them on
staff because you were senior if you
just were to go for a staff interview
there's some requirements of certain
number of years of experience or those
types of blocking things that you might
not have control over so how do you get
interview and great question CU that was
actually something that I was really
stunned by with airb because that
interview they were actually
interviewing me for one or the other
they were like we might give you senior
we might give you staff they were saying
like based on how you interview and I
was like because I actually got the
offers from uh Facebook and Google first
and then I got the Airbnb one and cuz I
was like ah dude because when those two
came in at senior I'm like like Airbnb
don't do it don't do don't do me don't
do me like this but then Airbnb comes in
his staff and I'm like okay then that
makes it very easy and you're totally
right the role the staff role at least
on the job description says 10 plus and
at that point I had six and I'm like 10
plus and six that's that's there's a gap
there there like a significant Gap I
think it comes back to just that impact
story and being able to talk about what
I did at Netflix and like the being like
I interfaced with these like 11 teams
and we solved all these crazy security
problems right being able to just talk
about all that stuff that is uh what I
think really put airb be over the edge
because one of the things that I feel
very grateful from Netflix that I know
impressed people people at Airbnb was
they have this kind of culture of this
feedback culture right the radical
cander of just give feedback immediately
right it's like almost if you come from
a a Kinder company or a more chill
company when you come into Netflix and
then you start getting this immediate
feedback you're like everyone here's a
dick everyone here's like why is
everyone here so mean but then after a
while you're like wait a minute no
everyone here really wants me to grow
that's what it's actually about and I
think that was what I was able to learn
from and get that but I was definitely
really nervous about the role at Airbnb
because I was like am I just walking
right back into what I just left at
Netflix right am I walking right back
into something that it was going to be
just a replication of what I was doing
before for the senior and the staff was
the recruiter up front where they're
saying Hey FYI you're either going to be
senior staff good luck on the interviews
yeah they they actually did say that and
I was annoyed by that a little bit
because I just felt I'm like I guess
because I knew that at that moment if it
was just a senior interview I wasn't
going to take it because was there
something on your end that you did to
advocate for staff oh yeah great
question so I advocated for staff
because in in that interview I was like
hey I'm interviewing at these other
companies and when I was talking with
the the Airbnb recruiter I was like hey
I'm interviewing at Facebook and at
Google right now as well and those
companies like if and I even told him
I'm like if I get an interview from all
three of you and they all come in at
senior I'm not picking Airbnb you said
that to yeah
right so were they gonna do senior yeah
I think so I I think that was well the
interview they said that's why we leaned
into that kind of Middle Ground of we'll
just do the interview and if you
interview well enough because I wanted
it to be like an open-mindedness at
least of give this guy a chance but yeah
because otherwise because everything
being equal I probably would have gone
back to Facebook if it was like senior
across the board I probably would have
gone back to Facebook got it like but
since it was not I was like and did you
try to get staff interviews at Google
and Facebook too yeah I did try to get
those they did not give me that straight
out at the front they said senior only
but Airbnb they said oh probably senior
you said I'm not going to take it unless
staff's an option and then they said
okay maybe staff and then you had the
opportunity and you did well on the
interviews yeah okay yeah it was wild
and I love that that's why it's so
important to have more than one company
that you're interviewing for that you're
excited about because then that puts you
in this position where you can have
conversations where hey this is what I
need from this company and because
otherwise I'm gone I'm just going to go
somewhere else and how many years of
experience did you have at that point
six yeah it was six actually I had a
viral post on LinkedIn about this where
the Airbnb rooll said I needed 10 and I
applied and it was six and I got it and
then my whole point on that post was
like apply for jobs that you don't think
you're ready for yeah yeah yeah so your
ability to negotiate and sell is what
got you that that stuff okay definitely
and actually like after being in that
role for a little bit I was ready for it
because you want to know what I realized
I realized more about the Netflix role
that
was more problematic than I thought it
was it was that I changed ladders right
I went from data engineer to software
engineer but then I went up that ladder
to staff and so in some ways like I was
just not ready to do software
engineering at that staff level because
honestly I'd been doing it like
professionally one year and the only
reason that I was able to like even not
just get absolutely crushed was because
I'd been spending all my weekends doing
it and like doing side projects and and
hustling on the side but if you look at
the actual professional experience it
was the combination of those two things
that I think was like brand new like job
role but also higher job title and those
two things together was like burnout
risk whereas like when I got in at
Airbnb it was like staff data engineer
I'm like okay I feel pretty good about
this it was like more the leadership was
there and I was like okay I needed to
grow in there a little bit but it it was
more manageable it didn't feel like it
wasn't like oh my God I have so much to
learn it was like okay there's things I
need to learn but I know what they are
and this is going to be doable that was
what I want to ask you is now because
you went into the staff role some might
wonder would you underperform in that
role you're saying that you performed
fine because it was going back to data
engineering which you had a lot more
confidence in is that right yeah and
that because I think at Netflix it was
the combination of getting put into this
position of high-risk position of and
like leadership ship position when I
wasn't ready for it but then it was the
combination of that and that I
transitioned to software engineering
like less than a year before and so
those two things together were I think
where there was a gap right where it's
you only want to change like one
variable at a time and then so when I
got in at Airbnb and I was nervous about
it for sure super nervous because I was
like I don't want to just run myself
right back into the ground being in a
position where I'm like I am not ready
for this but it was ended up being way
more chill for sure yeah and then your
first year at Airbnb how was the
performance yeah I got exceeds my first
half at Airbnb and it was a good one
like I think that first year I really
started to get the I just up leveled a
lot of the pricing pipelines and then I
built a lot of designs it was a lot
higher level kind of stuff and then they
also wanted me to they said I was close
with greatly because the problem was
architecture stuff right they really
wanted me to be working on things that
were companywide and I just wanted to
work on Marketplace they wanted me to
design the best practices of how to take
data from the data Lake and put it back
in the production systems because
everyone has taking data from production
putting it in the lake that's going the
other way is not as like straightforward
and they wanted me to come up with all
those and I just had no desire to do
that and then and that's when I realized
that was a moment there I had a Moment
of clarity I remember it was in
September of 2021 when I was like wait a
minute do I even want to get promoted am
I good where I'm at right now do I not
even care cuz I don't know I just feel
like I'm someone who like I want to do
everything that is asked of me and I
want to always be showing that next
level growth that's like a part of my
life and when I didn't want to do that I
literally was like I don't want to do
this work I don't want to do it and I I
told my manager I'm not going to do this
work and they're like okay that they
even told that if you don't want to do
that work that's the work that would get
you promoted that's the work that's
going to get you to the next level but I
just don't care it's too many meetings I
just did not like the fact that it was
just so many meetings so did your cuz
you said earlier your vision for your
career was as principal engineer by age
did that change then cuz cuz they were
handing you they were handing me the
path right up for sure that's exactly
what they were doing and I think it was
when I recognized this was also right
when I was getting traction on LinkedIn
at the same time I was like that's I
just hit 50k on LinkedIn or something
like that I was like wait a minute I
actually care about other things now I
don't just care about my job I care
about this other stuff as well and so I
told my manager I'm like it's fine I
will just work my job and that was like
my goal was like wanted to just get
Airbnb to more of a rest invest kind of
situation where I'm just doing the
absolute bare minimum what I wanted to
do throughout your story at Facebook and
at Netflix you had a really strong
internal brand with your manager and so
I think opportunities came to you he
kept giving you stuff get you to go
higher and higher yeah it sounds like a
Airbnb even without that manager's trust
people again were giving you opportunity
so what did you do at Airbnb to go from
zero internal brand to a point where
they're saying here's senior staff
please help us oh oh that's a great one
this is one of the things that I try to
do every time I get a new job is I want
to do something in three months where
people are like damn they're like okay
this guy's crazy and the thing that I
did in in three months at Airbnb was so
they have this pipeline called the
pricing and availability pipeline that
computes all the prices and availability
every day and it was like a mess it was
like one of the most like deaddy
freaking pipelines I have ever seen they
had this new notion called the paved
road which is the way you're supposed to
build a pipeline that is compatible with
the platform high quality and all they
had given me that to move that pipeline
onto the road but they said that was
something finished by the end of the
year I finished it in the first quarter
instead of four quarters and they were
like okay this guy clearly knows how to
make things a lot better and because
that made it so pipeline was no longer
delayed pipeline just worked and
everything was just smooth and pretty
much Flawless going forward and that was
the start of that first that's the first
like trigger in like someone's brain
because they're like first off they're
like this guy didn't just ramp up really
quickly he ramped up and landed a big
impact quickly those two things together
are are really important where I want to
show them that I don't really care that
much about risk right that like I manage
risk really I know that this pipeline is
very important for the whole company
it's a price is a very important part of
Airbnb
and so I was like we can figure this out
and we're going to build this out and
I'm just going to be very careful and
follow all the best practices and let's
get this done I try to do that I I try
to find those points in systems where
people know that things could be a lot
better but they don't want to touch it
because it's too risky or too complex or
too much of a pain in the ass it's
usually one of those three and that that
that's why people just let it be bad or
let it be suboptimal and there's I know
I have a gift for finding those points
of like where it's okay I can this
problem but I don't know if this is the
right one to solve but I'll do it and I
want to land an impact early that's the
big thing to start building that brand
and did you know that work would have
the impact before you did it or was that
kind of handed to you or so it was
handed to me obviously it's handed to
you when you if if you're three months
into a job like everything is handed to
you at that point right it takes at
least six months before you can build
your own internal kind of compass of the
company where you sit especially in
these big companies that like have so
any moving parts that's the only way to
do it but in this case it was like it
was something that was handed to me but
I think it's an interesting kind of
trade-off right and the goal there is
just to build that brand when you're
starting a new job people don't trust
you they honestly don't trust you some
people might actually distrust you I
know that there were some senior
engineers at Airbnb who actually didn't
like me because I got hired in that
staff because they were like they've
been gunning for staff and like that
staff promo from senior to staff is just
unnecessarily ridiculous at most
companies right and then they they
thought it was just handed to me cuz I
got hired in there and they're like oh
why is this external hire getting this
one I've been grinding for 4 years
trying to get this promo yeah that shows
to the value of interviewing because you
did something that very impressive too
you you did it and you got this offer
with like less than six months of work
whereas these other people they go
through all the hoops and things and
yeah still they're having troubles I
guess it shows the value of interview
it's similar to a couple things I think
a couple other pieces of that are like
you know how when like startup companies
are Venture Capital pre-revenue
companies actually get more generous
offers because it's the maybe right it's
like where could this go but then it's
like when you have a track record the
inertia that you have built from your
own track record it's hard to overcome
even if it's great still can be hard
because they're going to always be like
we hired you at this level and then you
have to fight it upwards that's why yeah
interviewing is wild yeah I think cuz
there's more variance in the interview
process There's an opportunity for you
to step you get that stepwise right it's
not an angle change it's a step change
yeah that's huge okay so that kind of
does the whole story of ic3 to ic6 and
what you did two halves at Facebook you
did about two halves at at Netflix you
had a break for roughly a year so you
basically went from Junior to staff in
three three four years yeah that's
insane okay so I think a few questions
wrap up the interview yeah one of the
most common ones that I get is how much
did you work it sounds like you're
working about 60 hours hours especially
60 hours a week at Facebook and Netflix
what about Airbnb was that Airbnb was a
lot better in
2021 like 40 maybe a little bit more
like that was one of the things that
blew my mind about getting the exceeds
yeah because I was like I'm not even
what I was like I I I actually thought
that my initial read on that was like
wait a minute you can get exceeds and
just work a normal amount of hours that
was something that I didn't didn't even
think was possible I thought I was going
to get Meats I thought I was going to
get meats and I'm like great I'm I'd be
happy with Meats I'm fine just don't
fire me I've definitely met people who
are afraid of the staff promotion
because they think that it locks them
into a lot greater than 40 hours a week
this is proof that in many CA or at
least in this one case you don't need to
work more than 40 hours a week and you
can meet expectations it's more about
shifting your behavior right it's about
shifting from you really need to be able
to start identifying High leverage
opportunities right and that's not
necessarily something that is grindy
right that's just something that like
you need to learn how to do and I think
that it can be grindy for some people in
staff and I think that's why some people
like they do feel like they need to like
work more but also sometimes like those
opportunities are just not there too
It's Tricky yeah definitely I think one
of the things that might be interesting
to go over is there something you
think's unique to your personality that
kind of helped you throughout yeah
that's a good one I think a couple
things there like the biggest one for me
is just my tenacious ability to just
keep learning and and I'm willing to put
in the work to do it cuz even when I was
doing 60 hours a week at Facebook I also
founded a startup during that time and
then Saturday and Sunday at the same
time I was also working on a startup
then because I wanted to learn
JavaScript and I wanted to get better at
full stack development I wanted to learn
how to do all stuff which has been
critical for My Success this year as an
entrepreneur because now I have this
platform that's all JavaScript based and
I'm like I'm so happy that I did that
even though back then I was like this is
my whole life I'm just sitting in front
of a computer and oh my God this is so
crazy I think that's one thing I think
another angle that I think is important
for me is that I'm a positive person I
think that another thing that's very
important is being excited to work like
showing up to work and being like I'm
excited to be here I'm happy to be here
is an underrated trait because the thing
is if you are showing enthusiasm and
excitement it's contagious it makes
other people like their jobs more and if
they like their jobs if they like their
jobs more because of you they like you
and if they like you they're more likely
to give you opportunity and that helps a
lot I know that's my friend nikot she's
doing crazy good at meta and I think
that like for her that's a big part of
it too is just like being able to get
people to like you and trust you and
build up especially as you get into
leadership and manager I feel like it's
like a manager's entire job is that
right is is is to get you to like your
job and so I think that's going to be
the other big one I think there's one
other angle that I think is for me I
don't know if being positive is unique
about me but I think the third angle
that I think for me is that I am not
willing to put up with [__] like when I
think something is unfair I'm willing to
change my life than just deal with it
which I think is a double-edged sword I
think I don't think that it's
necessarily always a good thing I think
that there could have been I think I
could have done like a similar career
trajectory as you if I would have just
stayed at meta and found another manager
who was better and pushed that way and
probably would have been like less
chaotic for me like in terms of all
these new companies all these health
insurance plans all these 401ks you know
how many 401ks I had to get because of
all this like it's had to merge all of
them it's pain in the ass that's still
the same thing though cuz even at meta
you'd have to not be satisfied with your
current one and be willing to switch
teams which is yeah still taking a risk
being okay with risk is a very important
part of this journey for sure yeah and I
think that first trait is a large part
of why your first manager even trusted
you so much if you have someone on your
team that's willing to put in those
insane hours or have that impact yeah
the manager is going to keep trusting
you with more if if you can show your
manager that you're going to stick with
a problem until it's solved yeah yeah
then they're like okay yeah here's more
work here's more important work yeah
cool and then last thing is if you were
to start all over again as ic3 knowing
what you know today MH what's one thing
that you change ooh that's a good one I
think that there's a couple angles there
one is
being
like more open to more perspectives
because I feel like my first couple
years in big Tech I was just very
focused on I need to just get my tech
skills up very high just become like the
most technical person ever and now
recognizing that that really only
matters to get to senior engineer for
the most part like after that like
technical skills do help a little bit
but it's more marginal after senior
engineer you need other skills to get
past that and feel like I didn't really
start to develop a lot of those soft
skills until I was at Netflix and things
were on fire and that's when I was like
okay time to learn the soft skills right
when I need them like when I desperately
need them and I think had I spent a
little bit more time at Facebook
focusing on those things developing the
soft skills in lower risk situ
so that like failure doesn't feel so
crazy that is I think something that
would have helped me a lot have a better
work life balance and probably grow
faster in my career I think that is a
big one that I definitely would have
changed I think another one I would have
changed that is important is don't eat
dinner at work don't do it just don't
eat dinner at work it's a scam dude it's
a scam because they offer it because
they get an Roi right that's the only
reason and Facebook and Google all these
companies they do not offer you dinner
because they're just beautiful amazing
great companies the only reason it's
there is to keep you at the office
longer and to get you working more live
your life take those hours right because
I think that was another thing because I
didn't really get into fitness until
2018 like my first year at Netflix and I
feel like had I taken those hours back
and dedicated them to the gym or
dedicated them to other areas of my life
that would have been another way that
things could have been so given your
super fast career growth are you saying
that you wish you worked less though and
was it worth it or the career growth I
think is worth it because it's another
way to go about doing your life my
vision now of my life is more of a
vision of balance and a a vision of
tranquility and peace I'm trying to
manifest that in my life now I wouldn't
want to do it again now right I wouldn't
want to go back and do what I did from
22 to 25 do those three years again no I
wouldn't want to do it again but do I
regret it no I think that it was what I
needed at the time to feel powerful it's
what I needed at the time to grow into
the person I'm supposed to be but with
that being said your health matters a
lot and I think that's an angle that
people forget about when they're like do
TC chasing is that okay but it's okay
say you make $20 million or whatever
working in big Tech but you stressed out
the whole time and you get cancer and
you die when you're 50 it's that a good
life you got to be thinking about those
other angles right health wealth
happiness they all matter and at
different points in your life they
matter different amounts that's why
looking at it now it's different but I
think that it's a strategy so it's if
you want that's definitely a way to go
if you want to go really and honestly I
think as especially young men who are
seeking purpose working really hard is a
great option it's actually a really
great option because it makes you useful
it makes you useful because like when
you're a teenager you're not really
useful and you got to learn and grow and
build something that makes you useful
for society and that is I think it gave
me a sense of purpose and that's great
but could I have gotten that sense of
purpose without grinding so hard and
having so many like sleepless nights and
so many like nights where I felt like I
was in over my head and a couple panic
attacks you there's a lot of other kind
of behind the scenes things there that
weren't really talked about like growing
the career that like I think are
important that things that like aren't
discussed as much so if you could go
back and talk to ic3 Zack yeah you'd say
stop being one-dimensional but still
keep working hard at at work but make
sure you take care of your health
and enjoy the ride more enjoy the ride
more and not get laser focused on that
and Laser focused on I must get promoted
it's everything will come to you in time
right if you put in the hours every day
and you're showing up every day you'll
get what you want the universe gives you
exactly what you want if you're willing
to put in the work and pay the price
thanks so much for your time Zach really
appreciate you coming on the podcast if
you made it this far thanks for
listening I am going to start posting
these career story podcasts since I
think it's helpful to to learn from
others' experience when I was growing
the staff I had a lot of help from
mentors who shared this kind of
information with me in one-on-one
conversation so I'm hoping this podcast
can make that information more
accessible when I asked to interview
Zach I wasn't fully prepared for the
video side of things we just recorded
this with our smartphones it's not the
best but it serves as a good starting
point uh for us to improve from so yeah
we were literally crammed right behind
me in my tiny room in SF but yeah it was
fun and if you have any feedback for me
on how to make this podcast more helpful
I'd love to hear it in the comments I'll
read every comment that I get here and
yeah thanks for listening once again
appreciate it